Josh Harrison

UI/UX Developer with 9 years of experience creating streamlined and intuitive controls and user experiences through programming and design. Talented at architecting and creating high-fidelity prototypes based off of lo- and hi-fidelity designs. Consistently employs understanding of web accessibility requirements and best practices.

EXPERIENCE

Intuit, Boise, ID — Frontend Staff Software Engineer

AUGUST 2022 - PRESENT

- Co-led a team of 4 junior web developers to deliver a seamless integrated experience with QuickBooks Online and QuickBooks Time using iframe APIs, React, JavaScript, and QuickBooks theming
- Created initial proof-of-concept and framework for the time tracking integration resulting in product delivery in 6 months vs 5 years using iframe APIs, React, and JQuery
- Built the first reusable plugin using React, HTML, and CSS for the time tracking integration to support theme-switching and design tokens that could be used across all Intuit products
- Worked across teams and three internal design systems to drive web and accessibility standards and adopt design system components and tokens
- Created prototypes using React, HTML, and CSS based off of customer interviews and lo-fi designs to support design/UX concepts, prove technical feasibility, or suggest alternatives

Intuit, Boise, ID — Time Tracking Accessibility Leader, Staff Software Engineer

AUGUST 2021 - AUGUST 2022

- Built a culture for accessibility that consisted of ~120 volunteer champions across development, customer support, product management, design, and research
- Created and taught an accessibility awareness class to introduce the organization to customers with disabilities, assistive technologies, and role-specific guides

CONTACT

Caldwell, ID, 83607 (916) 817-9230 joshharrison626@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jjharris on https://ioshharrison626.githu

https://joshharrison626.githu b.io/portfolio/

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, SCSS

Responsive Web Design

Wireframing and Prototyping

Web Accessibility Standards

Assistive Technology

JavaScript (Native, Libraries, and Frameworks)

UI Frameworks (React)

Reusable UI Components (Material-UI, Custom)

Figma (Dev Mode)

Documentation, Presentation, and Teaching

Creativity and Innovation

AWARDS

Accessibility Champion –
Subject Matter Expert (Intuit)
This award recognizes Intuit's
Accessibility leaders. They
lead accessibility efforts for
products and locations. They
help guide product design and
development for the future of

- Led customer interviews to learn how features were used with assistive technologies and report bugs
- Delivered Intuits 2nd VPAT by working with an external contractor to provide an accessibility audit and lead volunteers to remediate 15 features using Microsoft Accessibility Insights and axe DevTools
- Built a visually-hidden accessibility toolbar and custom keyboard shortcuts using React, HTML, and CSS and published an accessibility help guide to support customers using keyboards and screen readers
- Created a method of tracking keyboard analytics to prove accessibility usage, bug fixes, and feature discoverability; Published a blog describing the method and presented at Knowbility's AccessU 2021

Intuit, Boise, ID — *Sr. Software Engineer*

FEBRUARY 2019 - AUGUST 2021

- Led a small team of web and mobile engineers to deliver features based on location services
- Created and supported reusable web components to support location services and features
- Co-published a patent for determining location based on nearby devices (IPR-2011747US)

Intel, Hillsboro, OR — Web Developer

JANUARY 2015 - JANUARY 2019

- Built and supported reusable and branded web components for all Intel IT developers
- Supported web applications built on multiple JavaScript frameworks (React, Angular, AngularJS, etc.)
- Built proof-of-concept applications to prove and drive framework adoption (React vs Vue)

EDUCATION

B.S. in Network and Communication Management, *DeVry University*

4.0 GPA

A.S. in Electrical and Computer Technology, DeVry University

• 4.0 GPA

Intuit.

VOLUNTEER WORK

https://chairthehope.org/

Active volunteer: international wheelchair distributions; participate in local projects, fundraising, and create corporate partnership opportunities

ARTICLES

Accessibility features in QuickBooks Time

<u>Lessons Learned from an</u>
<u>Intuit Accessibility Champion</u>
- Intuit Blog

<u>Proving accessibility is worth</u> <u>it with analytics</u> - Intuit Blog